TRAN MINH KHOA

SITE RELIABILITY ENGINEER

DETAILS

ADDRESS

Ho Chi Minh City Viet Nam

PHONE

0976940300

EMAIL

khoatm2109@gmail.com

DATE / PLACE OF BIRTH

09/21/1994 Saigon

NATIONALITY

Vietnamese

SKILLS

Git

Linux

Kubernetes

Docker

CI/CD

Service Mesh Istio

GCP

AWS

C#

Terraform

Initiative and Problem-solving Abilities

JIRA

Confluence

LANGUAGES

English

 \bullet \bullet \circ \circ

HOBBIES

PROFILE

Working as Site Reliability Engineer over 2 years. I'm proactive. When I think about things, I do them. I like to see results and it's important in this role to be proactive and responsible for your own actions. Socially adept, offering a friendly and helpful attitude, and the ability to problem-solve well. A high-energy individual, with the ability to multitask and work well under pressure.

EMPLOYMENT HISTORY

Site Reliability Engineer, One Mount Group

Ho Chi Minh City

Nov 2019 — Present

- Config CI/CD process using Gitlab, always try organize Repository structure with highest convenient for develop team.
- · Using Kaniko Cache to optimize build speed up to 30% with GCP Cloudbuild.
- · Have knowledge about GCR, Kubernetes Engine, Dockerfile.
- · Have knowledge about Kong API Gateway.
- Build infra to deploy Superset Data Visualization, using Python to custom Superset code for suitable with company business.
- Using Service Mesh Istio multi cluster for increase security, internal traffic, monitoring.
- Using Grafana, Prometheus, Kiali, Skywalking for monitoring all cluster in
- · Estimated cost, safety, and reliability during the design processes.
- Using K6 for service performance test, scability test to ensure System always High Availability.
- · Using Splunk to manage service logs.
- · Apply Velero to backup/migrate Kubernetes resources and persistent volumes.

DevOps Engineer, FPT Software

Ho Chi Minh City

Aug 2018 — Oct 2019

- · Config Jenkins CI/CD process for all of project at FPT Software.
- · Using Covertiy Scan, Sonar Scan, BlackDuck Scan to improve code of product.
- · Code shellscript to deploy product to Cloud (Azure, AWS)
- Using some AWS services (VPC, S3, EC2, CodeDeploy, CodeCommit, Auto Scaling...) to standardize a project process in Cloud.
- Build full process CI/CD in AWS with Cloud team using CodePipeline and Blue/Green Deployment using ECR, ECS, CloudFormation, VPC, ELB for FPT Software AWS MSP Certificate.

System Administrator/Developer, FPT Software

Ho Chi Minh City

Oct 2016 — Jul 2018

Developer:

- Code shellscript Linux to import Oracle data in client side to Oracle Internal Server.
- Maintain and upgrade custom library of customer base on CakePHP (using PHP language)

Guitar Classic Motorbike RnB Singer Whiskey Lover Boxing Gym

- Join core team of C# project to get a system's business of customer and make a Detail Design for develop team
- · Get Project Management Fundamental Certificate of FPT

System Administrator:

- · Manage Virtual Machines for all of project in Business Unit 19
- · Config Linux to deploy source PHP using Apache
- · Setup private VLAN for Business Unit 19 with IT team
- $\cdot\;$ Setup Foglight tool to use for measure Oracle SQL query performance

Quality Control Engineer, FPT Software

Ho Chi Minh City

Apr 2015 — Sep 2016

Automation Tester:

· Using Java Selenium Webdriver for automation test

QC Leader:

- · Using Selenium IDE for training fresher.
- $\cdot\;$ Lead 10 members, support Developer debug & fix bug.
- · Implemented quality control standards.
- · Provided quality control over documents as required.

EDUCATION

Bachelor, FPT Polytechnic College

Ho Chi Minh City

May 2012 — Apr 2015